{
    "id": "61b3b8e89bd147a9921a2e9573a69ef2",
    "title": "English Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "One day we ……………………………… colonize Mars.",
            "description": "We cannot use can to talk about future ability. Instead we use will be able to.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "will be able to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She has no interest …………………………. politics.",
            "description": "Interest is followed by the preposition in.",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "in",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I was happy ……………………….. my old friends again.",
            "description": "We use a to-infinitive after happy.",
            "answers": [
                "to see",
                "seeing",
                "to seeing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Parents must discourage children ……………………………. unhealthy habits.",
            "description": "We use from + ing form after discourage.",
            "answers": [
                "to develop",
                "from develop",
                "from developing"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She is your neighbor, …………………………?",
            "description": "We use a negative tag after an affirmative statement. ",
            "answers": [
                "is she",
                "does she",
                "isn't she"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "It was …………………………… that we did not go out.",
            "description": "We use ‘so + adjective / adverb + article + noun’ in this pattern.",
            "answers": [
                "so cold day",
                "so a cold day",
                "so cold a day"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We were prevented ………………………… the class.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to enter",
                "from entering",
                "of entering"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is time you …………………………… to home.",
            "description": "We use a past tense with a present meaning after it is time.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "went",
                "have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The driver was …………………………. injured in the accident.",
            "description": "Fatally is the adverb. Deadly is an adjective.",
            "answers": [
                "deadly",
                "dead",
                "fatally"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I recommend ……………………….. go on a diet.",
            "description": "We can use a that-clause after recommend. A to-infinitive is not possible.",
            "answers": [
                "for you to",
                "that you",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They made me …………………………. the whole story.",
            "description": "We cannot use a to-infinitive after make.",
            "answers": [
                "to repeat",
                "repeat",
                "repeating"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I knew his real motive, I ………………………….. this.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not",
                "would not",
                "would not have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}